<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Barbarian - Path of Tranquility</name>
		<source>DM Secret Weapons</source>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="barbarian-path-of-tranquility.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/DM-Secret-Weapons/refs/heads/main/Subclasses/barbarian-path-of-tranquility.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Path of Tranquility" type="Archetype" source="DM Secret Weapons" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_BARBARIAN_PATH_OF_TRANQUILITY">
		<supports>Primal Path</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The primal force of Rage is as unwieldy as it is powerful. Warriors who harness it are called barbarians, known for their brutal savagery and blinding fury in battle. In you however, Rage is no master— it is a force under your command. It steadies your mind and enhances your senses. The wisest know well to fear the anger of a gentle soul; yours is the gentle soul they fear.</p>
			<p class="indent">Tranquility barbarians are masters of the primal energies that flow through them. Such warriors are focused, calculating, and devastatingly effective in combat, wielding Rage not as a sledgehammer, but as a scalpel. Far from wrathful brutes, they are often eloquent and gentle, but the perceptive might glimpse the fire that smolders behind their eyes. The fury within warriors who walk this path is under control, but remains just as potent as the fire that burns within any barbarian. They are tenacious and brave, speak softly, and carry a very large stick.</p>
			<div element="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_TEMPERED_FURY" />
			<div element="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_HEIGHTENED_INSTINCT" />
			<div element="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_CALCULATED_AGGRESSION" />
			<div element="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_STALWART" />
			<div element="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_WATCHFUL_WARRIOR" />
			<div element="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_FLOW_STATE" />
			<div element="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_EXPLOSIVE_STRIKE" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The primal force of Rage is as unwieldy as it is powerful. Warriors who harness it are called barbarians, known for their brutal savagery and blinding fury in battle.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_TEMPERED_FURY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_HEIGHTENED_INSTINCT" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_CALCULATED_AGGRESSION" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_STALWART" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_WATCHFUL_WARRIOR" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_FLOW_STATE" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_EXPLOSIVE_STRIKE" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Tempered Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="DM Secret Weapons" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_TEMPERED_FURY">
		<description>
			<p>Your rage focuses and fortifies your mind. While raging, you have bonus to Intelligence and Wisdom saving throws equal to your Rage damage bonus.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While raging, you have bonus to Intelligence and Wisdom saving throws equal to {{barbarian rage:damage}}.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Heightened Instinct" type="Archetype Feature" source="DM Secret Weapons" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_HEIGHTENED_INSTINCT">
		<description>
			<p>The steely mastery you have cultivated over your own rage makes you more astute than most. You gain proficiency in the Insight and Animal Handling skills, and you can add your Strength modifier to checks you make with those skills.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can add your Strength modifier to checks you make with Insight and Animal Handling skills.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING" />
			<stat name="insight:misc" value="strength:modifier" />
			<stat name="animal handling:misc" value="strength:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Calculated Aggression" type="Archetype Feature" source="DM Secret Weapons" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_CALCULATED_AGGRESSION">
		<description>
			<p>You have the focus to unite ferocity with calculating technique in combat. You learn the Great Weapon Fighting fighting style or another fighting style of your choice from the Fighter list. You can change your chosen fighting style for another from the Fighter list anytime you level up.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You learn the Great Weapon Fighting fighting style or another fighting style of your choice from the Fighter list. You can change your chosen fighting style for another from the Fighter list anytime you level up.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style (Calculated Aggression)" supports="Fighting Style,Fighter" default="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Stalwart" type="Archetype Feature" source="DM Secret Weapons" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_STALWART">
		<description>
			<p>Your unshakable tenacity in combat lends confidence to your companions. Allied creatures within 10 feet of you are immune to the frightened condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Allied creatures within 10 feet of you are immune to the frightened condition.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Watchful Warrior" type="Archetype Feature" source="DM Secret Weapons" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_WATCHFUL_WARRIOR">
		<description>
			<p>Your focus in battle is unparalleled, letting you flawlessly track and predict your foes. Creatures cannot have advantage on attack rolls against you as long as you aren’t incapacitated.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Creatures cannot have advantage on attack rolls against you as long as you aren’t incapacitated.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Flow State" type="Archetype Feature" source="DM Secret Weapons" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_FLOW_STATE">
		<description>
			<p>Your hyper awareness and mastery of mind and body allows you to enter a trance-like state in battle. When you make an attack roll while raging, you can choose to begin concentrating (as if concentrating on a spell) and enter this flow state, which lasts until your Rage ends or you lose concentration.</p>
			<p class="indent">While in a flow state, your movement speed increases by 10 feet, you have advantage on Intelligence and Wisdom saving throws, and when you take the Attack action and reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you can immediately use a bonus action to leap up to 30 feet and make a single weapon attack.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you enter this flow state, you cannot do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>When you make an attack roll while raging, you can choose to begin concentrating (as if concentrating on a spell) and enter this flow state, which lasts until your Rage ends or you lose concentration.&#13;
			While in a flow state, your movement speed increases by 10 feet, you have advantage on Intelligence and Wisdom saving throws, and when you take the Attack action and reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you can immediately use a bonus action to leap up to 30 feet and make a single weapon attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Explosive Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="DM Secret Weapons" id="ID_DMSW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANQUILITY_EXPLOSIVE_STRIKE">
		<description>
			<p>Your mastery of the primal fury that dwells within allows you to unleash it at the most devastating moment. Once per turn, when you hit a creature with a weapon attack while raging, you can expend a further use of your rage to deal additional damage to the target equal to your Strength score. You can use this feature a number of times per day equal to half your Strength Modifier (rounded up), regaining all expended uses when you finish a Long Rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{strength:modifier:half:up}}/Long Rest" action="1/Turn">
			<description>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack while raging, you can expend a further use of your rage to deal additional damage to the target equal to {{strength:score}}.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>